Tampere, Finland +358504805190 junsheng.fu@tut.fi

Junsheng Fu

GitHub Patents Homepage

I am an experienced researcher, a problem solver and an open source lover, passionate about autonomous driving, with 8 patents applications and 5 papers. I like to think "what if" and "how to", and enjoy applying Computer Vision and Deep Learning techniques to solve the challenges in autonomous driving.

Technical skills

Languages: Python, Matlab, C/C++

Frameworks: TensorFlow, Keras, CUDA, OpenCV, Scikit-learn,

Others: Camera pose estimation, Structure-from-motion, Machine Learning, Tracking, SLAM, Git, Linux

Projects

Model Predictive Control

Demo

7.2017

• Implemented a Model Predictive Controller (MPC) to drive a car autonomously in a game simulator.

Vehicle localization Demo

6.2017

• Implemented a real-time particle filter to estimate the position and orientation of a moving vehicle.

Sensor fusion-based tracking

Demo

5.2017

Designed and implemented Extended Kalman Filter and Unscented Kalman Filter for object tracking.

Vehicle detection

Demo

• Created vehicle detection and tracking pipeline with two approaches, deep neural networks (YOLO+TensorFlow) and support vector machines (HOG+OpenCV).

Camera Pose Estimation

Demo

4.2017

 Estimate the 6 degree-of-freedom camera pose of the query image based on a reference image and point cloud.

Lane departure warning

Demo

3.2017

Designed and implemented a lane-departure-warning system based on a monocular camera.

Driving behavioral cloning

Demo

2.2017

Built and trained a CNN to steer a car autonomously in a game simulator, using TensorFlow and Keras.

Experience

Tampere University of Technology

Doctoral Student

Finland | 1.2014-12.2017

- Implemented 10 autonomous driving demos with OpenCV, Python, Keras, and TensorFlow (videos).
- Working on camera pose estimation with LIDAR and street-view images.
- Served as teaching Assistant for "SGN-13006 Introduction to Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning", and got the best course reviews award from students in 2016 Fall Semester.

Nokia Research Center (Nokia Tech) Computer Vision Researcher

Finland | 3.2012-12.2015

- Designed and implemented a 3D Map Augmented Photo gallery application with HERE Map (video).
- Developed an Interactive Video Playback System with HERE Map (video).
- Implemented 3D reconstruction and visualization systems for indoor 3D smart sensing.

Tampere University of Technology

Research Assistant

Finland | 9.2010-12.2011

- Designed and implemented a real-time video denoising filter with C.
- Embedded a denoising filter into H.264/AVC codecs.

Demola

Software Engineer

Finland | 3.2010-8.2010

Implemented a face tracking application in Nokia N900 mobile phone with OpenCV and QT.

Education

Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Computer Vision, Ph.D.	GPA: 4.83 / 5	2017
Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Signal Processing, M.Sc.	GPA: 4.45 / 5	2012
Hangzhou Dianzi University, China - Telecommunication, B.Eng.	GPA: 85 / 100	2009
Udacity - Self-Driving-Car Engineer Nanodegree		2017

Patents & Publications

- US20170132843A1, A Method and Technical Equipment for Determining a Pose of a Device, published 2017 (link).
- US 20160248985, Device with an Adaptive Camera Array, published 2016 (link).
- WO 2016102768 A1, Monitoring, published 2016 (link).
- EP 3051410 A1, An Apparatus and Associated Methods for Provision of Wireless Power, published 2016 (link).
- US 20160191796, Methods and Apparatuses for Directional View in Panoramic Content, published 2016 (link).
- US 20150155009, Method and Apparatus for Media Capture Device Position Estimate-Assisted Splicing Of Media, published 2015 (link).
- US 20140300775, Method and Apparatus for Determining Camera Location Information and/or Camera Pose Information According to a Global Coordinate System, published 2016 (link).
- US 20150109508, Method And Apparatus for Generating a Media Capture Request Using Camera Pose Information, published 2015 (<u>link</u>)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, K. Roimela, Y. You, and V.-V. Mattila: "A 3d Map Augmented Photo Gallery Application on Mobile Device", IEEE ICIP 2014, France (link)
- J. Fu, J.-K. Kämäräinen, A. Buch, and N. Krüger: "Indoor Objects and Outdoor Urban Scenes Recognition by 3D Visual Primitives", ACCV workshop 2014, Singapore (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, Y. You, and K. Roimela: "Augmented and Interactive Video Playback Based on Global Camera Pose", the 21st ACM Multimedia, 2013, Spain (link).
- L. Fan, J. Fu, Y. You, K. Roimela, P. Piippo and V.-V. Mattila, "Deja Vu: A 3D map augmented photo gallery application on mobile devices", In IEEE ICCV 2013, Demo session, Australia.
- J. Fu, E. Belyaev and K. Egiazarian: "Rate-distortion Oriented Joint Video Pre-filtering and Compression", the 10th conference of FRUCT, 2011, Finland (<u>link</u>).
- Junsheng Fu, Master Thesis 2011: A Real-Time Rate-Distortion Oriented Join Video Denoising and Compression Algorithm (link).

Honors and Activities

TUT Graduate School Scholarship	2016-2017
Nokia Foundation Scholarship	2014
Sisu Award, NRC Multimedia Technology Lab	2013
Runner-up in IIDA Idea Innovation Competition	2011
Outstanding Graduate Award, Zhejiang China	2009
Chairman of Tampere Chinese Student and Scholar Association	2014-2015
Chairman of one Badminton Club in Tampere	2012